canadianblackbook.com 2018-10-14

# Canadian Black Book Car Values, New & Used Cars, Prices, Reviews & Research

Disclaimer: In case of discrepancy or litigation, the original official English version of these rules and regulations will prevail.

Canadian Black Book respects your privacy and is committed to protecting the personal information that you share with us. Generally, you can browse through our website without giving us any information about yourself. If or when we do need your personal information to provide services you request or when you choose to provide us with your personal information, this policy describes how we collect and use your personal information.

## 1\. Information Collection

Personal information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, email address, a home, postal or other physical address, title, birth date, gender, occupation, industry, personal interests, and other information when needed to provide a product or service you request.

We do not automatically collect personal information, including your email address. We do collect the IP (Internet protocol) addresses of all visitors to our website and other related information, such as page requests, browser type, operating system and average time spent on our website. We use this information to monitor and improve our website. We do not link your IP address to any personal information unless you have logged into a subscriber account.

Canadian Black Book collects personal information when you register with Canadian Black Book for a Canadian Black Book subscriber account, when you use certain Canadian Black Book products or services, when you register to attend a seminar or participate in an online survey, when you ask to be included in an email or other mailing list, when you submit an entry for promotions, or when you submit your personal information to Canadian Black Book for any other reason. Canadian Black Book only uses information if it has been collected in accordance with acceptable privacy practices and applicable laws.

Access to certain Canadian Black Book web pages is only available to subscribers and requires a login and a password. The use of those web pages and the information or programs downloadable from those sites may be governed by a written agreement between either you or your employer and Canadian Black Book. Unless you request deletion of your personal information as specified below, your personal information may be retained by Canadian Black Book to verify compliance with the agreement, log software licenses granted, track software downloaded from those pages, or track usage of other applications available on those pages.

When you browse our website, you do so anonymously, unless you are a subscriber to our service(s) and have previously indicated that you wish Canadian Black Book to remember your login and password. In that instance we can determine which subscriber account is browsing our website; however, we do not know whether the individual using the subscriber account is the individual registered to that account. For example, if you have provided your login to someone else or otherwise allowed someone else to use your account, we do not know who is using the subscriber account.

Like many other commercial websites, the Canadian Black Book website may use a standard technology called a "cookie" to collect information about how you use the site. Please go to "Cookies and Tracking Information" below for more information.

## 2\. Notice

When personal information is collected, we will inform you at the point of collection of the purpose for the collection. Canadian Black Book will not disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent, except under the limited conditions described under "Information Sharing and Disclosure" below.

We will always give you the opportunity to "opt in" to receiving direct marketing or market research information. This means we assume you have NOT given us your consent to collect and use your personal information in accordance with this Policy unless you take affirmative action to indicate that you do consent by clicking or checking the appropriate option or box at the point of collection.

## 3\. How We Use Information Collected

Canadian Black Book uses information for several general purposes: to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, to personalize your experience on our website, to keep you up to date on the latest software updates or other information we think you would like to hear about and to better understand your needs and provide you with better services. Additionally, your information may be passed to a third party business for the purpose of that business contacting you or otherwise providing information, products or services you may have requested. As stated above, this would only be done if you have expressly consented to such disclosure, or asked for information from a particular business.

## 4\. Information Sharing and Disclosure

Your personal information may be shared with other Canadian Black Book offices and subsidiaries or affiliates. All such entities are governed by this Privacy Policy or are bound by the appropriate confidentiality and data transfer agreements.

Your personal information is never shared outside Canadian Black Book without your permission, except under conditions explained within this document or as may be required by law. Inside Canadian Black Book, data is stored in controlled servers with limited access. Your information may be stored and processed in Canada or any other country where Canadian Black Book, its subsidiaries, affiliates, or agents are located. If your personal information is processed and stored in another country, that country's governments, courts, law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your personal information under the laws of that country.

Canadian Black Book may send your personal information to other companies or people under any of the following circumstances: when we have your consent to share the information; we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested; we need to send the information to companies who provide services on our behalf such as data processing, account administration, analytics and marketing (we will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose); or, if you have opted in, to keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, software updates, special offers or other information we think you would like to hear about either from us or from our business partners. We will also disclose your personal information if required to do so by law; to enforce our Terms & Conditions of Use; in urgent circumstances, to protect personal safety, the public, or our websites; and in connection with a sale, merger, transfer, exchange or other disposition of all or a portion of our business, in which case the successor will possess your personal information.

## 4.1 CBB FinancialTM

CBB FinancialTM is a service offered by Canadian Black Book in conjunction with Travelers Financial Group and Inovatec Systems Corporation (together the “CBB FinancialTM Partners”). The Personal Information you provide to us in connection with this service will be electronically transmitted to the CBB FinancialTM Partners, who may then disclose it to lenders and credit bureaus to:   
• verify your identity;   
• determine your eligibility for financing from lenders;   
• comply with legal or regulatory requirements, or as otherwise permitted by law;   
• protect against fraud and manage risk; and   
• respond to any questions you may have.   
We only collect the Personal Information that we determine we need for the above purposes. For example, we may collect:   
• Contact Information including address, telephone number and email address.   
• Social Insurance Number (SIN) to ensure an accurate match between your personal information and credit bureau information and to help us differentiate customers who may have the same or similar names.   
• Financial Information to ensure that the advice and/or products we and the CBBI FinancialTM Partners provide to you are appropriate for you.   
• Employment Information, including information about your previous and current employers, to confirm your eligibility for certain products.

Canadian Black Book, the CBB FinancialTM Partners, or lenders may collect personal information about you from you and from third parties or sources that are available to the public, including credit bureaus and lenders.

You can choose not to provide us with certain information in some situations, but if you make this choice, we may not be able to provide you with the product or information you request.

Canadian Black Book and our CBB FinancialTM Partners may monitor or record our incoming or outgoing telephone calls with you to ensure accuracy, security, service quality, for training purposes, and to establish a record.

## 5\. Third Party Sites

The Canadian Black Book website may at times contain links to other websites operated by third party companies. Some of these third party sites may be co-branded with a Canadian Black Book logo even though they are not operated or maintained by Canadian Black Book. Canadian Black Book does not share your personal information with those websites and is not responsible for the privacy practices of websites operated by third parties that are linked to our site. Once you have left our website, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party website to determine how they will handle any information they collect from you.

## 6\. Data Security

Your Canadian Black Book account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. Canadian Black Book safeguards the security of the data you send us with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. In certain areas of our website, Canadian Black Book uses industry-standard SSL-encryption to enhance the security of data transmissions. While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit to us, and so we urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet. Change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure browser.

## 7\. Cookies and Tracking Technology

A cookie is a small data file that certain websites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you have visited; however, the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Some parts of the Canadian Black Book website use cookies to track user traffic patterns. We do this in order to determine the usefulness of our website information to our users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information.

If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our website, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser, although you may not be able to take full advantage of the Canadian Black Book website if you do so. You may be required to accept cookies in order to complete certain actions on our website; however, you do not need to have cookies turned on to browse many parts of our website.

## 8\. Children and Privacy

Our websites do not target and are not intended to attract children under the age of 16. Canadian Black Book does not knowingly solicit personal information from children under the age of 18 or send them requests for personal information.

## 9\. Your Ability to Review and Delete Your Account and Information

You may review your personal information by contacting our Chief Technology Officer at 1-800-562-3150. You may also request deletion of your Canadian Black Book subscriber account or any of your personal information held by us by sending an email to info@canadianblackbook.com.

## 10\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

Canadian Black Book will amend this policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information we will make that information available by posting a notice on our website.

## 11\. Questions or Suggestions

If you have questions or concerns about our collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information, please contact Chief Technology Officer, Canadian Black Book, Inc., 7800 Woodbine Avenue, Suite 302, Markham, Ontario L3R 2N7, 1-800-562-3150 or info@canadianblackbook.com.

This document was last updated August 17, 2017.
